Guide to the Western Americana Card Photograph File
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Unidentified Photographers, circa 1850-circa 1951; Series II; 359
  - Portraits
    - Studio portraits
      - Unidentified individuals
        - Studio portrait of an Osage Indian woman, circa 1870-1872; 20.3 x 14.1 cm on mount 25.2 x 20.4 cm (Box 23)
        - Studio portrait of an Apache Indian man posed crouching with a rifle, circa 1880; 14.6 x 9.7 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 23)
        - Studio portrait of a group of thirteen young women and a girl, circa 1890-1895; 21.8 x 18.2 cm on mount 21.8 x 18.2 cm (Box 23)
        - Studio portrait of a man wearing a ribbon for a reception of the Trans-Mississippi Commercial Congress in Cripple Creek, Colorado, 1901 July 16-19; 15.2 x 11.0 cm on mount 22.7 x 16.9 cm (Box 23)
- Oversize Photographs, 1868-circa 1935; Series III; 83
  This series consists of photographic prints and their accompanying mounts that have dimensions greated than 22 x 29 cm (8.7 x 11.4 in.) in size and created by identified and unidentified photographers. Materials with smaller dimensions are located in Series I and Series II.
  This series is identified into two subseries: Identified Photographers and Unidentified Photographers.
  - Identified Photographers
    Photographs in this subseries series are organized in alphabetical order by surname of the photographer or the corporate name of a studio and then chronologically and by image subject.
    - Bailey, Frank Clinton
      Photographer in Spokane, Washington
      - Fire department, Spokane, Washington, 1890-1896; 15.9 x 20.0 cm on mount 25.5 x 30.3 cm (Box 24 (Oversize))
        Manuscript on verso: "When Lewis G. Meeks was in the department"
    - Bradley & Rulofson
      - Studio portrait of an unidentified man posed standing, circa 1875; 44.8 x 39.2 cm on mount 55.3 x 47.5 cm (Box 29 (Oversize))
        Ink inscription on verso: Clayton
        Gift of David Doret, 2013
    - Boston Railroad Photo Car
      A traveling photography studio railcar based in Sacramento, California
      - Men at railroad depot in Carlin, Nevada, 1895 Jul; 20.4 x 25.4 cm on mount 25.5 x 30.5 cm (Box 24 (Oversize))
    - Burge, Joseph C. (1839-1897)
      - Kingston, New Mexico, 1885-1891; 29.8 x 42.9 cm on mount 39 x 47.8 cm (Box 24 (Oversize))
    - Collins, William J. (1867-1938)
      Photographer in Rapid City, South Dakota
      - Corbin Morse Ranch roundup outfit, near Rapid City, South Dakota, circa 1900; 19.7 x 23.8 cm on mount 25.4 x 30.5 cm (Box 24 (Oversize))
    - Commercial Museum (Philadelphia, Pa.)
      Commercial Museum, also known as the Philadelphia Museums, was a group founded in 1894 to promote American and foreign commerce and to collect information concerning the products of world trade
      - Grain Elevators. Deloraine, Manitoba, circa 1903; 18.1 x 23 cm on mount 25.4 x 30.5 cm (Box 24 (Oversize))
        Printed identification on recto and verso.
        Image Number 3
    - Davidson, Isaac Grundy (1884-1891)
      - Mesa in the American Southwest, circa 1878-1888; 10.4 x 16.6 cm on mount 27.8 x 35.5 cm (Box 24 (Oversize))
      - Muir Glacier, Alaska, circa 1878-1888; 12.0 x 20.4 cm on mount 27.8 x 35.5 cm (Box 24 (Oversize))
        Image number 232
      - Muir Glacier, Alaska, circa 1878-1888; 12.1 x 20.4 cm on mount 27.8 x 35.5 cm (Box 24 (Oversize))
        Image number 238
    - Farciot, Charles O. (1839-1891)
      Photographer for a prospecting trip to Alaska with Edward Lawrence Schieffelin (1847-1897)
      - View of snow-covered landscape surround the village of Nuklukayet, Alaska, on the Yukon River, 1882-1883; 18.1 x 23.4 cm on mount 27.7 x 25.4 cm (Box 24 (Oversize))
    - Gardiner, Roswell H.
      Part of series, "God Bless Our Home, On the Line of the Oregon Pacific Railroad"
      Advertisements on verso for Oregon Development Company and the Oregon Pacific Railroad
      - Mess house, government works, circa 1890; 18.3 x 23.7 cm on mount 28.0 x 35.5 cm (Box 24 (Oversize))
        Image number 30A
      - House with small trees in foreground, circa 1890; 17.5 x 22.5 cm on mount 28.0 x 35.8 cm (Box 24 (Oversize))
        Image number 72A
      - Five men and women in front of a house, circa 1890; 18.5 x 23.8 cm on mount 28.0 x 35.5 cm (Box 24 (Oversize))
        Image number 25A
    - Hall, William
      - Men on the platform of the Northern Pacific Railroad depot in Elliston, Montana, circa 1890; 19.9 x 24.4 cm on mount 25.4 x 30.5 cm (Box 24 (Oversize))
    - Haynes, Frank Jay (1853-1921)
      Photographer in Fargo, Dakota Territory; Saint Paul, Minnesota; and for the Northern Pacific Railroad Company
      - Cascades Rapids of the Columbia River, circa 1880-1885; 16.7 x 21.9 cm on mount 25.4 x 30.4 cm (Box 24 (Oversize))
        Image in the series, "Scenery Along the Northern Pacific Railroad"
      - Mount Hood, Oregon, circa 1880-1885; 21.5 x 16.8 cm on mount 30.6 x 25.4 cm (Box 24 (Oversize))
      - Two men salmon fishing, in the Columbia River, Oregon, circa 1885; 16.7 x 21.9 cm on mount 25.3 x 30.6 cm (Box 24 (Oversize))
      - Multnomah Falls, Columbia River, Oregon, circa 1883; 21.9 x 16.5 cm on mount 30.4 x 25.3 cm (Box 24 (Oversize))
        Mounted on the verso of a mount for a Yellowstone National Park series
    - Hillers, John K. (1843-1925), attributed
      - Studio portrait of three Seneca Indian men, identified as Samuel Jimson, Caster Redeye and Harrison Halftown, 1877; 19.8 x 13.8 cm on mount 28.1 x 25.4 cm (Box 24 (Oversize))
        Manuscript notes on recto that include the height, head and chest measurements of each man. Identified from left to right as Dyar-yo-naa-darga-dah (One Who Carries Hemlock Boughs To Back) or Samuel Jimson (born circa 1831); Hoh-ho-i-yo (Splendid Deer) or Caster Redeye; and Dar-gar-swen-gar-ant (Dropping the Stock of the Gun) or Harrison Halftown (born 1830)
        Image attributed to Hillers, but individual studio portraits have been attributed to Charles Milton Bell and Alexander Gardner
        From the collection of Major Henry Elijah Alvord (1844-1904)
    - Jackson, William Henry (1843-1942)
      - United States Geological Survey en Route; the United States Geological Survey pack train on trail along the Yellowstone River, 1871; 17.2 x 22.4 cm on mount 27.8 x 35.6 cm (Box 25 (Oversize))
        Image number 303
        Brown letterpress captions on mount: "Department of the Interior. U.S. Geological Survey of the Territories. Prof. F. V Hayden in Charge" and "W. H. Jackson, Photo."
      - Studio portrait of the son of Donald McKay, circa 1873-1877; 22.4 x 17.1 cm on mount 35.4 x 27.7 cm (Box 25 (Oversize))
      - Informal portrait of Crown Indians, identified as Perits-Har-Sts, also known as Old Crow, and squaw, circa 1873-1877; 19.7 x 13.0 cm on mount 35.6 x 27.8 cm (Box 25 (Oversize))
        Image number 943
      - Manitou, Colorado, circa 1880; 24.5 x 33.5 cm on mount 40.5 x 50.6 cm (Box 25 (Oversize))
        Image number 248
        Cardstock mount chipping along edges
        Purchased from Michael Vinson on the Frederick W. and Carrie S. Beinecke Fund for Western Americana, 2012
      - Colorado Springs - Pikes Peak, circa 1890- 1910; 15.8 x 25.6 cm on mount 27.9 x 35.6 cm (Box 25 (Oversize))
        Image number: 3175
      - Salt Lake City, Utah, circa 1892-1900; 25.5 x 34.3 cm on mount 35.5 x 43.1 cm (Box 25 (Oversize))
        Image number 195
    - Jacoby & Barnes
      Photography studio in West Liberty, Iowa; partnership of F. C. Jacoby and Barnes
      - On the farm of C. L. Peck and C. D. Peck, Mechanicsville, Iowa, circa 1892; 19.2 x 24.0 cm on mount 25.3 x 30.5 cm (Box 25 (Oversize))
      - Residence of C. L. Peck and C. D. Peck, Mechanicsville, Iowa, circa 1892; 19.2 x 24.0 cm on mount 25.3 x 30.5 cm (Box 25 (Oversize))
    - Keleher, William Aloysius (1886-1972)
      - View of buildings at Fort Wingate, New Mexico, with fort in ruins, circa 1910; 20.4 x 25.2 cm on mount 25.5 x 30.5 cm (Box 25 (Oversize))
    - Marsh
      Photographer in Douglas, Wyoming
      - Sioux Indians imprisoned in Douglas, Wyoming, for murder of Sheriff William H. Miller of Weston County, also known as the "Lightning Creek Fight", 1903 Nov; 15.6 x 20.7 cm on mount 25.4 x 30.6 cm (Box 25 (Oversize))
        The names of the Indians are printed on the mount.
        A deep crack cuts diagonally across the photograph and the mount
    - McInnis, Hector C.
      - The Commercial Hotel, Sprague, Washington, before the fire, with proprietor George Fritz Benninghoff (1851-1926) in the foreground, 1895; 18.7 x 23.6 cm on mount 27.6 x 25.3 cm (Box 25 (Oversize))
    - Notman, William, & Son
      - Indian camp, Blackfoot Reserve, near Calgary, Alberta, 1889; 18.0 x 23.4 cm on mount 26.6 x 32.3 cm (Box 25 (Oversize))
        Image number 2156
    - Poley, Horace Swartley
      - View of the Katherine and Elkton mine works on Raven Hill near the town of Elkton, Colorado., 1895; 18.5 x 22.9 cm on mount 25.4 x 30.5 cm (Box 25 (Oversize))
        The Colorado Springs and Cripple Creek district train runs near the Elkton mine building, with mine tailings on either side of the tracks
    - Quale, Carlin Everett (born 1884)
      Purchased from aGatherin on the Frederick W. and Carrie S. Beinecke Fund for Western Americana, 2011
      - View of the Lyric Moving Picture Theater in Bridgeport, Nebraska, circa 1913; 19.3 x 24 cm on mount 30 x 35 cm (Box 25 (Oversize))
        Banner on theater advertises the Grand International Roping and Riding Contests held at Muskogee, Oklahoma
    - Reed & McKenney
      - View of Georgetown, Colorado, circa 1873; 14.7 x 20.4 cm on mount 24.6 x 30.4 cm (Box 25 (Oversize))
    - Reed, C. O.
      Photographer in Philipsburg, Montana
      All mounts inscribed: "Compliments of Frank D. Brown." Frank Dean Brown (1845-1931) worked for various mining companies in Butte and Philipsburg, Montana, and was the owner and editor of the Philipsburg Mail newspaper
      - Interior portrait of Frank Dean Brown (1845-1931) in his office in Philipsburg, Montana, circa 1890; 18.9 x 23.1 cm on mount 25.4 x 30.4 cm (Box 25 (Oversize))
      - Philipsburg, Montana, looking west, circa 1890; 19.2 x 24.5 cm on mount 25.4 x 30.4 cm (Box 25 (Oversize))
      - Granite Mountain, Montana, circa 1890; 18.9 x 23.1 cm on mount 25.4 x 30.4 cm (Box 25 (Oversize))
    - Shindler, Antonio Zeno (1823-1899)
      Photographer for the Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C
      - Studio portrait of Chief Jason, also known as Kalkalshuatash, Nez Perce Indian, 1868; 18.6 x 13.3 cm on mount 35.3 x 27.6 cm (Box 26 (Oversize))
    - Silvis, John B. (1830-1900)
      - View of Hailey, Idaho Territory, circa 1870-1882; 19 x 25.2 cm on mount 27.8 x 34 cm (Box 26 (Oversize))
    - Squire's Art Parlors
      Photography studio in Mount Vernon, Washington
      - Flood in Mount Vernon, Washington, circa 1895; 17.5 x 23.7 cm on mount 25.3 x 30.4 cm (Box 26 (Oversize))
    - Steaffens, Charles George (1868-1960)
      Photographer in Red Wing, Minnesota
      - Studio portrait of ten members of the Cataract Hose Company, No. 1, Red Wing, Minnesota, circa 1907; 17.4 x 22.6 cm on mount 28.2 x 35.6cm (Box 26 (Oversize))
        Ink inscription on verso identifies several members, including Charles August Fridell (1880-1975, Martin F. Knolle (1869-1930), August H. Maetzold (1871-1940), Henry Maetzold (1857-1910), William Christian Risse (1891-1957), and Casper Henry Tiedeman (1873-1930)
        Mount broken and split along its upper quarter
        Purchased from Vigilante Rare Documents on the Frederick W. and Carrie S. Beinecke Fund for Western Americana, 2010
    - Taber, Isaiah West (1830-1912)
      - Hotel del Monte, Monterey, California, circa 1880; 20.5 x 39.2 cm on mount 31.0 x 39.4 cm (Box 26 (Oversize))
        Image number A 119
      - Cliff House, San Francisco, California, circa 1880-1885; 21.0 x 30.7 cm on mount 35.5 x 46.0 cm (Box 26 (Oversize))
        Image number A 160
      - Joss Temple, Chinatown, San Francisco, California, circa 1887; 23.7 x 19.7 cm on mount 37.4 x 31.0 cm (Box 26 (Oversize))
        Image number B 2694
      - Interior of the St. Michael the Archangel Cathedral (Greek Church) at Sitka, Alaska, from the left of the altar, 1889; 19.2 x 24.2 cm on mount 27.2 x 34.6 cm (Box 26 (Oversize))
        Image number 4587
        Mounted on a photograph album board.
        Verso includes photographic prints by Taber of icons in the church, "St. Michael" (image number 4737) and the "Madonna" (image number 4738)
      - Interior of the St. Michael the Archangel Cathedral (Greek Church) at Sitka, Alaska, front view, 1889; 19.6 x 24.4 cm on mount 25.6 x 26.2 cm (Box 26 (Oversize))
        Image number 4588
    - Wittick, George Benjamin (1845-1903)
      - Studio portrait of a Navajo Indian, identified as Pedro, and his wife, circa 1885; 14.8 x 10.1 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.7 cm (Box 26 (Oversize))
        Pedro identified as a former scout with Captain Ben Rogers for the United States Army at Fort Wingate, New Mexico
      - Decoration of ballroom for Christmas Eve, E. Troop Second Cavalry, Fort Wingate, New Mexico, 1896 Dec 24; 19.5 x 24.0 cm on mount 25.4 x 30.5 cm (Box 26 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified Photographers
    This subseries is organized in alphabetical order by geographical locations according to states in the United States, then by photographs of locations in Canada and Venezuela, followed by images with unidentified locations arranged chronologically.
    - Alaska
      - Nome
        - Views of fishing ships along the shoreline and storefronts along the shore at Nome, Alaska, circa 1905; 6 photographic prints 16.2 x 21.1 cm and smaller on paper leaves 24.4 x 29.4 (Box 26 (Oversize))
    - California
      - Kings Canyon National Park
        - Two views of giant sequoia trees at Kings Canyon National Park, California, including the General Grant tree, circa 1885; 2 photographic prints 12.8 x 21.1 cm on mounts 42.4 x 35.3 cm (Box 26 (Oversize))
    - Colorado
      - Georgetown
        - View of a passenger train on the narrow gauge High Bridge trestle near the Georgetown Loop, a route over Clear Creek near Georgetown, Colorado, 22.0 x 31 cm, unmounted halftone (Box 26 (Oversize))
          Image number 61
      - Gold Hill
        - View of Gold Hill, Colorado, from a hill near the Horsfal Mine, circa 1895; 15.9 x 20.2 cm on mount 25.3 x 30.4 cm (Box 26 (Oversize))
      - Teller County
        - View from a distance that shows buildings and tailings of the Moose Mine at head of Arequa Gulch, Raven Hill, Teller County, Colorado, circa 1890; 18.5 x 22.9 cm on mount 25.5 x 30.6 cm (Box 26 (Oversize))
        - View of the Isabella Mine in Altman, Cripple Creek District, Teller County, Colorado, circa 1893-1910; 19.0 x 23.0 cm on mount 25.5 x 30.5 cm (Box 26 (Oversize))
        - View of Battle Mountain with the Bob Tail and Anna Lee mines in the Cripple Creek District, Teller County, Colorado., circa 1895; 18.7 x 23.0 cm on mount 25.5 x 30.5 cm (Box 26 (Oversize))
      - Unidentified locations
        - View of a town, probably in Colorado, circa 1880-1890; 18.7 x 24.5 cm on mount 25.5 x 30.7 cm (Box 26 (Oversize))
        - View of a mine with snow-covered landscape above a mountain town, probably in Colorado, circa 1890; 18.5 x 23.2 cm on mount 25.5 x 30.5 cm (Box 26 (Oversize))
    - Iowa
      - Lester
        - View of locomotive number 1214, probably of the Southern Pacific Railroad and two crew members in Lester, Iowa, 1907; 15.5 x 20.4 cm on mount 26.7 x 27.8 cm (Box 26 (Oversize))
    - Mexico
      - Victoria de Durango
        - Three photographs: two photographs depict a nine men near a ditch in a desert landscape with a human skull amd assorted items; the third photograph depicts a man from the group with another blindfolded man at a railroad, 1921 November 20; 3 photographic prints 11.7 x 19 cm and smaller on mount 37.9 x 27.5 cm (Box 26 (Oversize))
          Gift of Michael Vinson, 2009
          Ink inscription on verso of mount: Respetuosamente al Señor P.M. Hernández de su aff amigo y SS. Ramón Fernández A., Durango, Noviembre 23, 1921
          Dated on the verso
    - Montana
      - Billings
        - Interior portrait of George Fritz Benninghoff (1851-1926) in the office of the Grand Hotel, Billings, Montana, circa 1890; 15.0 x 20.6 cm on mount 25.4 x 30.6 cm (Box 26 (Oversize))
      - Butte
        - Interior portrait of ushers of the Maguire Grand Opera House, Butte, Montana, 1898; 20.5 x 15.2 cm on mount 31.8 x 26.8 cm (Box 26 (Oversize))
          Identified individuals in the image include Will Lloyd, Roy Recore, Raymond Rhule, Jack Maquire, Herschel Warfield, Chas Fiske, Jas Spencer, Kinky Holmes, and J. W. Gunn, Jr
    - Nebraska
      - Broken Bow
        - View of Broken Bow, Nebraska, looking north, circa 1885-1890 (Box 26 (Oversize))
    - Nevada
      - Goldfield
        - O'Keefe stagecoach draped in black cloth in celebration of its retirement with the construction of the Tonopah and Goldfield Railroad in Goldfield, Nevada, 1905 Sep 15; 19.6 x 24.2 cm on mount 24.8 x 29.8 cm (Box 26 (Oversize))
    - Oklahoma
      - Darlington
        - Scene at the issue of subsistence supplies to Cheyenne and Arrapahoe (sic) Indians at the U.S. Indian Agency at Darlington on the North Canadian River, Indian Territory (Oklahoma), 1872; 14.2 x 21.7 cm on mount 27.7 x 35.1 cm (Box 28 (Oversize))
          From the collection of Major Henry Elijah Alvord (1844-1904), with manuscript notes on recto
    - Oregon
      - Milton-Freewater
        - View of the building for Olinger Brothers Lumber Company and wagons full of lumber pulled by a team of horses, as well as the carpentry shop of David Wallace Olinger (1873-1930) in the background in Milton, Oregon, circa 1900-1905; 16.7 x 22.0 cm on mount 25.0 x 30.0 cm (Box 28 (Oversize))
          The Olinger Brothers Lumber Company was a partnership within the Olinger family that comprised of John Omar Olinger (1872-1919), David Wallace Olinger (1873-1930), Jasper Eldarado Olinger (1880-1970), and Franklin Morton Olinger (1881-1969)
    - South Dakota
      - Pine Ridge Indian Reservation
        - Overview of the Pine Ridge Indian Agency with the Ogallala Boarding School in the distance, 1899; 19 x 24.4 cm on mount 27.6 x 33 cm (Box 28 (Oversize))
          Ink inscription on verso
    - Utah
      - Homansville
        - Silver quartz mine of the Wyoming Silver Mining Company near and Pinion Mountain of the Tintic Mining District, Homansville, Utah, circa 1890; 16.2 x 22.4 cm on mount 28.2 x 35.5 cm (Box 28 (Oversize))
        - Silver quartz mine of the Wyoming Silver Mining Company near Homansville, Utah, circa 1890; 16.6 x 22.9 cm on mount 27.6 x 35.6 cm (Box 28 (Oversize))
    - Washington
      - Garfield
        - Group portrait of students in front of the Garfield School in Garfield, Washington, circa 1900; 19.4 x 24.6 cm on mount 25.3 x 30.5 cm (Box 28 (Oversize))
      - Sunnyside
        - Six men, probably the city council of Sunnyside, Washington, probably related to the incorporation of the city, 1902; 14.0 x 20.1 cm on mount 22.7 x 27.9 cm (Box 28 (Oversize))
          Probably members of the Progressive Brethren Church, which formed the Christian Cooperative Colony that organized Sunnyside. Man on the far left identified as Henry Wende
    - Wyoming
      - Hazelton
        - Sheep dipping pens at Hazelton, Wyoming, circa 1890; 15.5 x 20.7 cm on mount 22.7 x 27.9 cm (Box 28 (Oversize))
      - Shoshoni
        - Panorama of Shoshoni, Wyoming, which includes the depot for the Northwestern Railroad, circa 1910; 10.1 x 33.7 cm on mount 17.7 x 35.7 cm (Box 28 (Oversize))
          2 photographic prints form the panorama
    - Canada
      - British Columbia
        - Barkerville
          - View of Barkerville, British Columbia, and surrounding landscape cleared of trees, circa 1868; 16.9 x 26.6 cm on mount 24.5 x 30.8 cm (Box 28 (Oversize))
        - New Westminster
          - View of New Westminster, British Columbia, and the riverfront on the Fraser River, 1876; 18.5 x 23.1 cm on mount 25.0 x 30.4 cm (Box 28 (Oversize))
      - Saskatchewan
        - Battleford
          - Portable oil derrick for the Battleford Oil and Gas Company in Battleford, Saskatchewan, 15.3 x 20.7 cm on mount 25.0 x 29.9 cm (Box 28 (Oversize))
    - Venezuela
      - Informal portrait of six soldiers, probably army recruits in Venezuela, circa 1880; 17.7 x 23.3 cm on mount 23.8 x 30.4 cm (Box 28 (Oversize))
        Faint pencil inscription on recto: "Venezuela Army Recruits"
    - Unidentified locations
      - View of oak trees in a forest with a parasol beside one of the trees, circa 1870; 23.6 x 29.6 cm on mount 40.4 x 50.5 cm (Box 28 (Oversize))
      - Studio portrait of an elderly Piute Indian, identified as Chief Winnemucca, also known as Poito (died 1883), circa 1875; 35.6 x 28.3 cm on mount 35.6 x 28.3 cm (Box 28 (Oversize))
      - View of a family consisting of a man, woman, boy, and two girls, posed standing in front of a homestead near a forest, circa 1880; 20.6 x 24.7 cm on mount 25.4 x 30.5 cm (Box 28 (Oversize))
      - View of a farm, including outbuildings and farm implements, including plows, tractor, and wagons, as well as men and women, circa 1890; 18.5 x 24.0 cm on mount 24.2 x 30.8 cm (Box 28 (Oversize))
      - Copy photograph of an engraving of Stephen Fuller Austin (1793-1836), circa 1890-1900; 35.5 x 27.2 cm on mount 35.5 x 27.2 cm (Box 28 (Oversize))
      - Copy photograph of a painting of George Darius Kilborn (1853-1930) by Sir Hubert von Herkomer in 1923, circa 1935; 35.3 x 24.8 cm, unmounted (Box 28 (Oversize))
        Photogravure from the Dictionary of American Biography, accompanied by a smaller photographic print of the same image, a bookplate from the library of Kilborn, and a photocopy of a brief biography of him